<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book Notes on rowstu.net</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/</link><description>Recent content in Book Notes on rowstu.net</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rowstu.net/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book.Thinking</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/book.thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/book.thinking/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="key-lessons-from-dont-believe-everything-you-think"&gt;Key lessons from Don&amp;rsquo;t Believe Everything You Think&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking is an active process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts happen all by them selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two are similar but not the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopping thinking takes active effort and you quickly fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts unchecked will happen all by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simpler approach as prescribed by meditative philosophies is to simply watch the thoughts and do you best to not engage in thinking about the thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Do The Work</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/do-the-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/do-the-work/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="notes-from-do-the-work-by-john-bishop"&gt;Notes from Do the work by John Bishop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="no-more-excuses"&gt;No more excuses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have individual traits or behaviors that we struggle to get rid of. These could be perceived shortcomings in character, specific emotions, or particular habits that others may seem to handle effortlessly. Often, we become acutely aware of these “dark spots” and, instead of addressing them, adjust our lives to avoid the potential disruptions they might cause. In doing so, we erect a fortress of excuses to shield ourselves from confronting these truths.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Flow</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/flow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/flow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes on the book Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book explores the concept of &amp;ldquo;flow,&amp;rdquo; which is a state of mind characterized by total immersion in an activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In flow, people typically feel a sense of control, loss of self-consciousness, and enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book says that people are happiest when they are in a state of flow, and that achieving flow is essential for leading a fulfilling life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jim</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/jim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/jim/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="notes-from-the-book-jim-and-the-universe"&gt;Notes from the Book Jim and the Universe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;have faith that the universe knows what it is doing and it is so. Don&amp;rsquo;t doubt, doubt wil kill it. Live your life like it is so. Feel happy about it. Feeling is everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be grateful, say thank you to the universe all the time. Say it with sincerity and dont say it until you can feeeeeel the sincerity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;trust the universe. you don&amp;rsquo;t know, the universe knows.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Learn To Think Using Riddles Brain Teasers And Wordplay</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/learn-to-think-using-riddles-brain-teasers-and-wordplay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/learn-to-think-using-riddles-brain-teasers-and-wordplay/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="notes-on-learn-to-think-using-riddles-brain-teasers-and-wordplay-develop-a-quick-wit"&gt;Notes on learn to think using riddles, brain teasers and wordplay: develop a quick wit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;also refer to: &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/riddles/"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/riddles/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a riddle involves using divergent thinking which demands you analyse all possible solutions to a given problem. open up and expand ideas on what could possibly be happening in a scenario that a riddle poses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the opposite of divergent thinking is critical thinking, which requres operating within a strict set of rules in order to arrive at an answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Four Agreements</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/the-four-agreements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/the-four-agreements/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes on the book The Four Agreements by Don Miguel Ruiz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presents a code of conduct based on ancient Toltec wisdom. The agreements are principles aimed at achieving personal freedom and living a more fulfilling life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be impeccable with your word: This agreement emphasizes the power of language and encourages speaking with integrity. It means avoiding gossip, speaking truthfully, and using your words to spread love and kindness rather than negativity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Happiness Advantage</title><link>https://rowstu.net/books/the-happiness-advantage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/books/the-happiness-advantage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes on the book The Happiness Advantage by Shawn Achor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book states that happiness is not simply a result of success, but rather it is the cause of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultivating a positive mindset and outlook can lead to better health, stronger relationships, and greater success in all areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven principles that contribute to the happiness advantage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Happiness Advantage - happiness leads to success, not the other way around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fulcrum and the Lever - changing our mindset can help us leverage our potential for success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tetris Effect - our brains can become patterned to see either positive or negative patterns, and we can train our brains to see the positive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Falling Up - we can use adversity as an opportunity for growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zorro Circle - starting with small, manageable goals can help us gain control over bigger challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 20-Second Rule - making small changes that take 20 seconds or less can have a big impact on our habits and productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Investment - connecting with others and investing in relationships can lead to greater happiness and success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not just a byproduct of success, but it is a key driver of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>