<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security Notes on rowstu.net</title><link>https://rowstu.net/sec/</link><description>Recent content in Security Notes on rowstu.net</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rowstu.net/sec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kerberos</title><link>https://rowstu.net/sec/kerberos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/sec/kerberos/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="kerberos-notes"&gt;Kerberos Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerberos is a widely used authentication protocol developed at MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) that provides a secure method for authenticating users and services in a networked environment. It was designed to address some common security issues related to password-based authentication. Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of how Kerberos works&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="authentication"&gt;Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user wants to access a networked resource, they first authenticate themselves to the Authentication Server (AS) by providing their username and password.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ocsp Stapling</title><link>https://rowstu.net/sec/ocsp-stapling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rowstu.net/sec/ocsp-stapling/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ocsp-stapling"&gt;OCSP Stapling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCSP stapling, also known as TLS Certificate Status Request extension or the Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP) Stapling, is a security feature in the Transport Layer Security (TLS) and Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocols. It is designed to enhance the security and performance of SSL/TLS connections, particularly in web servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you visit a website secured with SSL/TLS, your browser typically checks the validity of the SSL/TLS certificate presented by the web server. One way to do this is by using OCSP (Online Certificate Status Protocol), which allows the browser to ask the certificate authority (CA) whether the certificate is still valid.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>